

JOSE ENRICO BANDONG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

RESUME OBJECTIVE

To acquire a job as a Front-End Developer.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 04/24/1986 (Age: 37)

Gender: Male

Contact: 080-4097-2102

Email: j.enricobandong@gmail.com

Address: Tokyo Prefecture, Toshima District

Closest Train Station: Otsuka Station – Yamanote Line (5-minute walk from house)

Portfolio Site:

https://jericfederer97.github.io/portfolio/

Github:

https://github.com/JericFederer97

Spoken languages: English & Japanese

SKILLS

Languages:

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

TypeScript

Python

Swift (Xcode)

Frameworks:

SwiftUI, React Native, ReactJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Django, Flask

Tools/Management Tools:

Git, Docker, Redmine

EXPERIENCE

<u>コグラフ株式会社(Co-graph Inc.)</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2020/09 - PRESENT

■ WEB OPTIMIZATION and FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECT

2022/01 ~ PRESENT

- Reduced page loading time by code refactoring and algorithm change
- · Develops front-end and back-end functionality
- · Develops code for bug fixes
- · Writes unit tests to ensure 100% of code is without bugs

LANGUAGE: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

FRAMEWORK: Invenio, React JS, Angular JS, Bootstrap, Flask

DATABASE: PostgreSQL SERVER: Docker TOOLS: Git. Redmine

■ ORACLE NETSUITE AND FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECT

2021/07 ~ 2021/12

FULL STACK DJANGO (Netsuite Data Use)

- · Developed front-end design and functionality
- · Developed back-end website functionality

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, Javascript FRAMEWORK: Bootstrap, Django

DATABASE: MySQL TOOLS: Git. Netsuite

■ FRONT END WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECT

2021/06 ~ 2021/07

- Designed and created web pages according to the website architecture
- · Google Map API implementation and customization

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

FRAMEWORK: Bootstrap TOOLS: Git, MySQL, Redmine

■ BACKEND WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECT (Data Engineer) 2021/04 ~ 2021/06

- Created scripts for inserting/updating data into the database
- · Created data validation scripts

LANGUAGE: Python DATABASE: MySQL SERVER: Local

TOOLS: Git, MySQL, Workbench

■ FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECT 2020/09 ~ 2021/03

Developed front-end and back-end functionality

LANGUAGE: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Python FRAMEWORK: Invenio, Angular JS, Ember JS, Bootstrap, Django,

lask

DATABASE: PostgreSQL

SERVER: Docker TOOLS: Git, Redmine

EDUCATION

2004/04 - 2008/08

AMA COMPUTER UNIVERSITY

BS Electronics and Communications

Engineering

2016/04 - 2016/10WASEDA EDU JAPANESE LANGUAGE
SCHOOL

CERTIFICATIONS

2016/12 Japanese Language Proficiency Test N3 2014/12 Japanase Language Proficiency Test N4

PROFILE

I am a Software engineer working in Tokyo,
Japan. I can speak both English and Japanese.
My experience using Python in my previous
company (Ranger Systems) sparked my
interest in programming and its possibilities.
As such, I have taken the initiative to study
various programming languages
and frameworks. I have found that it is
something I enjoy and am passionate about.

This new passion has served as the catalyst to make the career change to programming. I have experienced using various technologies in front-end and back-end web development in my current company. This has led me to discover that I want to specialize in Front-End and Mobile development.

I have studied both Swift and React Native. I have been making apps using SwiftUI in Xcode and React-Native in my own time.

As for Front-End development, I have studied and have been making small JavaScript projects using React JS (with and without TypeScript) and Vanilla JS.

INTERESTS

Playing the piano
Composing piano pieces
Music Production
Reading novels
Sports (Boxing, Tennis, Table Tennis)
Video games (Especially JRPGs)

EXPERIENCE

レンジャーシステムズ株式会社 (Ranger Systems) PYTHON DEVELOPER / NETWORK ENGINEER 2016/05 - 2020/08

- Developed data-extraction scripts for our network intelligence device and database using Python.
- Developed tools for routine operations use such as config checker, config change, automation and other scripts depending on what is required for a specific operation using Python.
- Monitored and troubleshot mobile data traffic issues, using a network intelligence device.
- Responsible for mobile data traffic speed upgrade / downgrade
- Responsible for network intelligence devices' maintenance (license/firmware update and RMA).

NTT COMMUNICATIONS - VIRTELA TECHNOLOGY SERVICES

NETWORK ENGINEER 2015/06 - 2016/03

- Dedicated network engineer for NTT Communications' clients (Japanese clients)
- Monitor network circuit issues via trouble ticketing system and provide
- Inbound/Outbound calls to clients and partner carrier/vendor (TELCOs)
- Responsible for configuration changes (speed upgrade/downgrade, additional features, etc)
- Responsible for creating network diagrams using Visio
- Responsible for testing and accepting new internet circuits (E1, T1, Ethernet, etc)

ACCENTURE

NETWORK ENGINEER 2012/04 - 2015/05

- Dedicated network engineer for a premium client who handles network Implementation and troubleshooting.
- Troubleshoot digital cross connects and Ethernet aggregators such as Anda Box, Tellabs switch and Nortel OME device
- Provide network engineering services to support customers on activating WAN connections and connecting them to MPLS-PIP network.
- Responsible for preparing configurations on provider edge routers for plug and play circuits.
- Build/disconnect ports and PVCs required by the design team and is responsible for configuration adjustments as required for management acceptance
- Communicate with internal technical groups, clients, field ops and telecommunications partner in troubleshooting a circuit.
- Coordinate with project managers and service & assurance team for order verification and assistance.
- Responsible for accurate back office system data record management.